Europe and North America are the two
欧洲和北美是世界上
most culturally and economically
文化和经济
interlin continents in the world. Yet,
联系最紧密的两个大陆。 然而，
an ocean stands between them. A colossal
他们之间隔着一片海洋。
number of people travel between the two
大量人员
for work, for family, or for fun, making
因工作、探亲或娱乐而在这两个城市之间旅行，使
the North Atlantic the largest and most
北大西洋成为世界上规模最大、最
valuable longhaul aviation market in the
有价值的长途航空市场
world. Logic would then follow that it's
。 由此推断，它是
market in the world. [music] And while
世界上竞争最激烈的远程航空市场。  [音乐] 虽然
it might look that way sitting at JFK
坐在肯尼迪
airport watching dozens of different
机场，看着几十家不同的
European airlines roll by, the logos
欧洲航空公司的飞机来来往往，但飞机
painted on the side are merely a facade.
侧面涂上的标志只不过是门面而已。
On the surface, it appears that 33
表面上看，似乎有 33 家
different airlines fly 126 different
不同的航空公司运营着
routes between New York and Europe.
纽约和欧洲之间的 126 条不同航线。
These are not only the big players like
这些不仅包括像
BA, Air France and KLM flying to major
英国航空、法国航空和荷兰皇家航空这样飞往
destinations like London, Paris and
伦敦、巴黎和
Amsterdam, but also plenty of smaller
阿姆斯特丹等主要目的地的大型航空公司，还包括
airlines like Air Serbia, High Sky or
像塞尔维亚航空、高空航空或
Azorus Airlines serving smaller markets
亚速尔航空这样服务于
like Belgrade, Bucharest or Ponta
贝尔格莱德、布加勒斯特或蓬
Delgata. This appears like a healthy
塔德尔加塔等较小市场的众多小型航空公司。 乍一看，这似乎是一个健康的
competitive landscape until you look
竞争格局，但仔细观察就会发现并非如此
closer. [music]
。  [音乐]
If you wanted to fly, say, to Brussels,
如果你想飞往布鲁塞尔，比如说，
you'd have a choice between a 6:10 p.m.
你可以选择下午 6:10 的航班。   搭乘
departure from JFK on Brussels Airlines
布鲁塞尔航空公司的航班从肯尼迪机场出发，
or a 6:30 from Newark on United. But
或搭乘美联航的航班于早上 6:30 从纽瓦克机场出发。 但
what you wouldn't have is a choice on
你没有选择
how much to pay [music] because almost
音乐票价的权利，因为
every single day the airlines are
航空公司几乎每天都
charging the same price. But there's a
收取相同的价格。 但这背后是有
good reason for this. Brussels Airlines
充分理由的。 布鲁塞尔航空
[music] and United are effectively
和美联航实际上就像
acting as a single airline. It's the
一家航空公司一样运营。
same thing for Munich. United operates a
慕尼黑的情况也是如此。 联合航空运营
515 from Newark, Lufansza A 530 from
从纽瓦克机场起飞的 515 航班，卢凡萨航空运营从
JFK, then another Newark frequency at
肯尼迪机场起飞的 530 航班，然后早上 8:30 又有一班从纽瓦克机场起飞的航班
8:30. All priced identically. This is a
。 所有商品价格相同。 这是一个
cartel. Not a drug cartel, but a
卡特尔组织。 不是毒品卡特尔，而是
business cartel. Brussels Airlines,
商业卡特尔。 布鲁塞尔航空、
United, Lufansza, as well as Swiss and
美联航、瑞士航空以及
Austrian Airlines are all colluding.
奥地利航空都在串通一气。
Together, they decide how often to fly,
他们共同决定飞行频率、
where to fly, and crucially, how much to
飞行地点，以及至关重要的——
charge individually. They don't care who
每位飞行员的收费标准。 他们不在乎谁
flies what because they pull
飞什么航班，因为他们赚取
transatlantic revenue, then distribute
跨大西洋航线的收入，然后
it according to the terms of their joint
根据
venture agreement. It doesn't matter to
合资协议的条款进行分配。 对
United whether a passenger takes them or
美联航来说，乘客选择乘坐他们的航班还是
Lufansza to Frankfurt. They'll earn the
Lufansza 的航班前往法兰克福并不重要。 无论如何，他们都会拿到
same amount regardless. This all means
同样的报酬。 这一切意味着，
that [music] from the perspective of
从
competition economics, these five
竞争经济学的角度来看，这五家
airlines are really acting as one. This
航空公司实际上是在像一家公司一样运作。 这
is intriguing. If you refer to article
很有意思。 如果您查阅《欧盟
101 of the treaty on the functioning of
运作条约》第101条，
the European Union, it reads, [music]
其中
quote, "The following shall be
写道：“下列各项均应被
prohibited as incompatible with the
禁止，因为它们与
internal market. All agreements that
内部市场不相容。所有
directly or indirectly fix purchase or
直接或间接固定
selling prices." It's hardly a secret
买卖价格的协议。”
that these airlines are price fixing.
这些航空公司操纵价格几乎是公开的秘密。
They'll happily discuss it with their
他们很乐意与
investors. This would leave any normal
投资者讨论此事。 这将使任何一家正常的
business in a world of legal trouble.
企业陷入法律纠纷。
But the United and Lufansza cartel has
但联合和卢凡萨卡特尔拥有
this. In this document, the European
这个。 在这份文件中，欧盟
Commission outlines their decision to
委员会概述了他们决定
exempt these airlines from antitrust
豁免这些航空公司遵守反垄断法的决定
law. This is a legally approved cartel.
。 这是一个合法认可的卡特尔。
European and American regulators have
欧美监管机构
allowed these airlines to collude
允许这些航空公司串通起来，利用
[music]
音乐损害
against the consumer. And it's not the
消费者利益。 而且这并非个
only such case. The next largest
例。 其次是
encompasses Delta, Virgin Atlantic, KLM,
达美航空、维珍航空、荷兰皇家航空
and Air France, representing about 26%
和法国航空，它们约占
of the transatlantic market from New
纽约跨大西洋市场的 26%
York. Then the third major transatlantic
。 第三家主要的跨大西洋
joint venture includes American
合资企业包括美国
Airlines, Air Lingus, British Airways,
航空、爱尔兰航空、英国航空、
Finire, Iberia, and Levelville,
Finire航空、伊比利亚航空和Levelville航空，
operating a further 18% of flights.
运营着另外18%的航班。
Together, this sums to 75% of all
加起来，这占
Eurbound flights from New York. 75% of
纽约飞往欧洲所有航班的 75%。 全球
all flights in the most lucrative
利润最丰厚的
longhaul market in the world are
长途航线市场中，75% 的航班
operated by just three entities.
由三家公司运营。
Regardless, it is still true that New
尽管如此，纽约机场面临的
European competition of any US airport.
欧洲竞争对手或许是美国机场中最强大的。
But that means that elsewhere, the
但这意味着在其他地方，
problem is even worse. In the smaller
问题甚至更严重。
market of DC, for example, these three
例如，在华盛顿特区这个较小的市场中，这三家
joint ventures encompass 85% of all
合资企业占据了 85% 的
transatlantic flights, severely stifling
跨大西洋航班，严重扼杀了
competition. And that stat will go up to
竞争。
89% soon if SAS and ITA Airways are
如果北欧航空和意大利航空按计划
granted approval to join the Sky Team
获准加入天合联盟
and Star Alliance joint ventures as they
和星空联盟合资企业，那么这一比例很快就会上升到 89%。
intend. Now, the majority of the legal
现在，
proceedings allowing for such collusion
允许这种串谋的大部分法律程序都
have taken place just a subway ride away
发生在距离达拉斯机场仅一趟地铁车程的
from Dallas airport at the US Department
美国
of Transportation. American law does
交通部。 美国法律确实
allow the DOT to grant antitrust
允许交通部给予航空公司反垄断
immunity to airlines, but there's one
豁免权，但有一个
key stipulation. They must deem that the
关键规定。 他们必须认为，
public benefits enabled by collusion
串谋带来的公共利益
outweigh the negative consequences of
大于
reduced competition. Therefore, airlines
竞争减少带来的负面后果。 因此，航空公司
submit long winding arguments to the DOT
向交通部提交冗长而曲折的论据，
explaining why, in their opinion, the
解释为什么他们认为
public would benefit so greatly from
公众会从
their collusion. One of the most recent
他们的串通行为中受益匪浅。 最近的
cases took place between 2012 and 2019
案例之一发生在 2012 年至 2019 年期间，
as Virgin Atlantic sought inclusion into
当时维珍航空寻求加入达
Delta's existing transatlantic joint
美航空现有的跨大西洋合资
venture. [music] To start, they pursued
企业。  [音乐] 首先，他们寻求
antitrust immunity on US UK routes.
在美国和英国航线上获得反垄断豁免权。
Their legal argument was all in support
他们的法律论据全部都支持
of this one line. Quote, "The joint
这一条。  “合资
venture will be a more effective
企业将
competitor on USUK routes. They explain
在美英航线上成为更有效的竞争对手。他们解释说，其
that the crux of the public benefit
公共利益的关键
would be quote the creation of a
在于‘创建一个
meaningful competitive alternative to
有意义的、能够与目前主导美英市场的
the alliance between American Airlines
美国航空
and British Airways that presently
和英国航空联盟相抗衡的替代方案’。
dominates the US UK market." The pair
” 两人
characterized their flight frequencies
认为飞行频率过高是导致
as a key cause of their ineffectiveness.
他们效率低下的主要原因。
What makes London in particular such a
伦敦之所以
valuable destination to airlines is that
对航空公司来说如此重要，是因为
it's a top origin and destination for
它是商务旅客的主要出发地和目的地
business travelers. And business
。 商务
travelers are more likely to purchase
旅客更有可能购买
costlier business class and lastminute
价格更高的商务舱机票和最后一分钟
tickets. But business travelers tend to
机票。 但商务旅客往往
also be very schedule dependent. They
也非常依赖行程安排。 他们
want to be away from home for as little
希望离家的时间越短
time as possible. Meaning if their
越好。 也就是说，如果他们的
meeting ends at 2 p.m., they want to be
会议在下午 2 点结束，他们希望
on a 5 p.m. flight home from Heathrow.
在下午 5 点开始。 从希思罗机场乘飞机回家。   经常
Large companies that require lots of
需要出差的大公司
business travel typically sign corporate
通常会
contracts with airlines in exchange for
与航空公司签订企业合同，以换取
reduced fairs and increased perks. But
更低的票价和更多的福利。 但
according to Delta, these buyers have
据达美航空称，这些买家曾
quote repeatedly told Delta its service
多次告诉达美航空，其纽约至伦敦航线的服务
frequencies and time of day coverage on
频率和时间覆盖
NYC to LHR are inadequate and have
不足，并
refused to commit business to Delta on
拒绝在该航线上与达美航空开展业务
the route. The trickiness was that Delta
。 棘手之处在于，达美航空
couldn't simply just add more London
不能简单地增加飞往伦敦的
flights. Heathro is one of the most
航班。 希思罗机场是世界
heavily slot restricted airports in the
上航班时刻限制最严格的机场之一
world. With just two runways, every
。 由于只有两条跑道，每个
landing slot is used, and demand so
着陆位都被使用，需求
severely outstrip supply that these
远远超过供应，以至于这些
slots sell for tens of millions of
着陆位的售价高达数千万
dollars. The most valuable slots are the
美元。 最有价值的航班时刻是
early morning arrival times used by
清晨抵达的
overnight transatlantic flights, just
跨大西洋夜间航班，这正是达
the type Delta needed. And even if the
美航空所需要的。 即使对
cost was worth it to them, slots only go
他们来说这笔交易物有所值，老虎机也只是
up for sale every so often.
偶尔才会出售。
venture with Virgin, they told the DOT,
他们告诉美国交通部，另一种方案是，如果达美航空与维珍航空成立合资企业，
they could coordinate their schedules to
他们可以协调航班时刻表，以
improve time of day coverage. They'd
改善一天中不同时段的航班覆盖。 他们将
keep the eastbound schedule the same. In
保持东行列车时刻表不变。 从
that direction, times don't matter as
这个角度来看，时间就没那么重要了，
much since they're almost all in the
因为它们几乎都在
evening. But for westbound flights,
晚上。 但对于西行航班，
they'd shift the schedule around to
他们会调整航班时刻表，
remove competing departure times and
消除相互冲突的出发时间，并
help improve coverage across the day so
帮助改善全天的航班覆盖，这样
that the longest gap would be the 3
最长的间隔将是
hours between Virgin's 5 and [music]
维珍航空下午 5 点和晚上
8:00 p.m. flights. Ultimately, the DOT
8 点之间的 3 小时。 航班。 最终，交通部
was compelled by Delta and Virgin's
被达美航空和维珍航空的论点所打动
argument and approved their antitrust
，批准了它们放弃反垄断
immunity waiver. But that approval acted
豁免权的申请。 但这种批准实际上是一种
as a tacit admission. If the public
默认。 如果
benefit for Delta and Virgin's joint
达美航空和维珍航空的合资企业带来的公共利益
venture was the creation of a strong
是创造了一个
competitor to American and British
与美国航空和英国
Airways' joint venture, that must mean
航空的合资企业形成强大竞争关系的竞争对手，那么这必然意味着
that American and British Airways' joint
美国航空和英国航空的合资
venture created a public detriment. So
企业造成了公共损害。
then why did the DOT approve American
那么，美国交通部为何在 2010 年批准了美国航空公司
and British Airways' joint venture in
和英国航空公司的合资企业呢
2010? Well, the crux of their argument
？ 他们的论点核心
was that Delta already had their own
是，达美航空已经拥有自己的跨
immunized transatlantic joint ventures
大西洋合资企业，
and that the formation of their own
而成立自己的合资企业
would make them a stronger competitor.
将使他们成为更强大的竞争对手。
So once again, why did the DOT approve
那么，美国交通部为何
Delta and Air France's joint venture in
在 2002 年批准达美航空和法国航空的合资企业呢
2002? Of course, Delta argued that it
？ 当然，达美航空辩称，这
would make them a stronger competitor to
将使他们成为
the already approved United Lufansza
已获批准的联合卢凡萨
joint venture. And why did the DOT
合资企业的更强大的竞争对手。 为什么美国交通部
venture all the way back in 1996? Well,
早在 1996 年就批准了 United 和 Lufansza 的合资企业？ 嗯，
that's where things start to make at
这样看来，事情至少开始变得
least slightly more sense. The original
稍微有道理了。
vision for transatlantic joint ventures
跨大西洋合资企业的最初愿景
was to expand the hub and spoke network
是将枢纽辐射式网络
model to both sides of the Atlantic.
模式扩展到大西洋两岸。
After deregulation in the 70s and 80s,
20 世纪 70 年代和 80 年代放松管制后，
airlines in the US and Europe rework
美国和欧洲的航空公司重新调整了
their route networks to operate most
航线网络，将大部分
flights to or from a limited number of
航班运营至少数几个
hub airports. They'd coordinate their
枢纽机场或从这些机场起飞。 他们会协调航班
schedules to have a big bank of flights
时刻表，让一大批航班在
arrive around the same time, then
同一时间到达，然后
another big bank leave shortly after, so
另一批航班很快离开，这样
passengers from big cities to small
从大城市到小型
[music] towns could have a huge array of
（音乐）城镇的乘客就可以有很多
conveniently timed connections. This
方便的转机选择。 这
dramatically increased consumer choice
极大地增加了消费者
for short-haul travel, but it had less
在短途旅行方面的选择，但对
of an impact for long haul. United, for
长途旅行的影响较小。 例如，美联航曾
example, flew to major European cities
飞往
like London, Paris, Zurich, and Rome.
伦敦、巴黎、苏黎世和罗马等欧洲主要城市。
But if you're going to a smaller
但是，如果你要去的是
destination that lacked United service,
美联航没有服务的较小目的地，比如
Bilbao or Leon or [music] Stoutgart, you
毕尔巴鄂、莱昂或斯托特加特，那么
were better off booking your flight with
最好预订
a European airline since they'd offer
欧洲航空公司的航班，因为他们会提供
European side connections onto their
欧洲境内的转机服务，以便搭乘他们的
short hall flights. But this still left
短途航班。 但这仍然让
some customers out. If someone was
一些顾客无法享受到服务。 如果有人
traveling from a smaller US city without
从美国一个没有
service from a European airline to a
欧洲航空公司服务的小城市前往
European destination without service
欧洲一个没有
from an American airline, they'd have a
美国航空公司服务的目的地，那么他们就
harder time getting a [music] fast and
很难找到快速且便宜的[音乐]
cheap itinerary. The idea through
行程。 通过
cooperation was to allow passengers to
合作，乘客可以
connect through hubs on both sides,
通过双方的枢纽站进行转机，将
combining the networks of Luanza and
Luanza 和 United 的网络结合起来
United, and therefore creating a far
，从而创建一个
larger, far more competitive and
更大、更具竞争力和更
convenient network. [music] Today, this
便捷的网络。  [音乐] 如今，这种
partnership has grown into a critical
合作关系已发展成为
core of the two airlines's businesses.
两家航空公司业务的关键核心。
Each morning, eight United wide bodies
每天早上，美联航的八架宽体客机将
bring well over a thousand passengers
一千多名乘客
into Lufansza's Frankfurt hub, and the
送至 Lufansza 的法兰克福枢纽，其中
majority of them continue their journey
大多数乘客会继续他们的旅程，
by making their way through the
穿过
airport's maze of terminals onto another
机场迷宫般的航站楼，搭乘
Lufansza flight. Through cooperation,
Lufansza 的另一架航班。 通过合作，
the German airline has coordinated their
这家德国航空公司协调了航班
schedule to make sure they have
时刻表，以确保能够
well-timed capacity to the destinations
及时提供飞往
popular with US origin passengers, but
美国乘客喜爱但
not otherwise serviced by United, like
美联航尚未提供服务的目的地（如
Stockholm, Vienna, or Istanbul. After
斯德哥尔摩、维也纳或伊斯坦布尔）的航班。
all, it's in their interest. Since they
毕竟，这符合他们的利益。 由于他们
pull transatlantic revenue, they want to
赚取跨大西洋的收入，他们希望
be sure that their network offers a
确保他们的航线网络能够提供
better, faster, cheaper itinerary than
比
through Amsterdam, Paris, [music]
经由阿姆斯特丹、巴黎、
London, or any other competitor's hub.
伦敦或任何其他竞争对手的枢纽机场更好、更快、更便宜的行程。
unquestionably been a net positive for
毫无疑问，这种网络整合对消费者来说是一件好事
consumers. It's expanded choice and even
。 它扩大了选择范围，甚至
injected more competition into the mix
引入了更多竞争，
as now United can compete to European
因为现在美联航可以与
destinations it doesn't directly serve
它没有直接服务的欧洲目的地展开竞争
as well. The benefits might even justify
。 这些好处甚至可能足以证明美国
the DOT's approval of their antitrust
交通部批准其反垄断
immunity. They might represent the
豁免的合理性。
harm if crucially the antitrust immunity
如果反垄断豁免权
was what made this [music] public
是使这种（音乐）公共
benefit possible. But it's hard to find
利益成为可能的关键，那么它们可能代表着大于公共损害的公共利益。 但很难找到这方面的
the evidence of that. United and Luansza
证据。 联合航空和卢安萨航空并
did not start integrating their networks
没有
in 1996 upon approval of their antitrust
在 1996 年获得反垄断
immunity [music] waiver. They did so in
豁免权（音乐）豁免后就开始整合其网络。 他们在
1993.
1993 年实现了这一点。
Passengers from Tampa, Orlando,
来自坦帕、奥兰多、
Philadelphia, New Orleans, and Phoenix
费城、新奥尔良和凤凰城的乘客
could now connect through Dallas airport
现在可以经由达拉斯机场转机
onto a flight to Frankfurt. then from
飞往法兰克福。 然后从
Frankfurt to eight German cities in
法兰克福飞往维也纳的八个德国城市
Vienna. And similar arrangements were
。
set up for Chicago and San Francisco.
芝加哥和旧金山也采取了类似的安排。
They didn't pull revenue or coordinate
他们没有互相拉拢收入或协调
pricing, but rather just paid each other
定价，而只是
sold as part of the other airlines
为对方航空公司
itineraries, steering clear of antitrust
行程中出售的对方航班上的座位付费，从而避免了违反
violations. It was not until 3 years
反垄断法。 直到三年
later that the two airlines applied for
后，这两家航空公司才申请
antitrust immunity with the argument
反垄断豁免，理由是他们
that it was needed to do the very thing
需要这样做才能做
they had already started doing. Now,
他们已经开始做的事情。 现在，
they made arguments on why they'd be
他们提出了各种论点，说明为什么
better incentivized to continue to do
继续做
what they were already doing. But
他们已经在做的事情会更有动力。 但
regardless of the truth of that, their
无论事实如何，他们的
antitrust immunity application presents
反垄断豁免申请将
the network integration as the core of
网络整合视为
the public benefit, the element that is
公共利益的核心，这是
legally required to outweigh the harms
法律要求的足以抵消
of reduced competition. This public
竞争减少所造成的损害的要素。
benefit, however, was clearly already in
然而，考虑到航空公司已经在实施这项政策，这种公共利益显然已经符合
the airlines's interests [music]
航空公司的利益（音乐）
implementing it. Further evidence of the
。 当今社会也进一步证明了
feebleness of this so-called public
这种所谓公共
benefit can be found in the present.
利益的薄弱。
American has a major partnership with
美国航空与卡塔尔航空建立了重要的合作伙伴关系
Qatar Airways. American operates flights
。 美国航空运营
from Philadelphia to Doha, which is not
从费城飞往多哈的航班，这条
a route that would normally turn a
航线
profit on its own merits, but it's
本身通常不会盈利，但
scheduled to arrive at the Middle
预计航班
Eastern hub around 4:30 p.m. with just
将于下午 4:30 左右抵达这个中东枢纽。
enough time for passengers to transfer
乘客有足够的时间转乘
onto Qatar's [music] 6 to 9:00 p.m.
卡塔尔航空的航班，音乐时间为下午 6 点至晚上 9 点。
eastbound bank and plenty do thanks to
东行银行和许多银行都通过
carriers. In the inverse, Qatar's US
航空公司提供的联程机票实现了这一点。 反过来，卡塔尔在美国的航线
network is formed around [music]
网络是围绕音乐而建立的。
Americans network with flights to most
美国人通过飞往
of their hubs, Los Angeles, Dallas,
洛杉矶、达拉斯、
Chicago, New York, and Miami. This is a
芝加哥、纽约和迈阿密等大多数枢纽城市的航班进行旅行。 这是
deep partnership. It's now the core of
深度合作。 现在，这已成为
how American serves the growing Middle
美国航空服务于不断增长的
East and India markets. While it's the
中东和印度市场的核心方式。 这是
primary way that Qatar expands [music]
卡塔尔将
its reach deeper into the US. What this
其音乐影响力进一步扩展到美国的主要方式。 但这
is not, however, is an antitrust
并非受反垄断
immunized joint venture. It's got all
豁免的合资企业。 它具备
the public benefits that airlines
航空公司
purport come with antitrust immunity.
声称享有反垄断豁免权所带来的所有公共利益。
Network integration, [music]
网络整合、[音乐]
schedule coordination, through ticketing
日程协调，通过票务系统，
while keeping Qatar and American as
同时保持卡塔尔航空和美国航空的
competitors. For a passenger going from
竞争关系。 对于从
say Boston to Delhi, [music] the two
波士顿飞往德里的乘客来说，这两家
airlines offer two different itineraries
航空公司提供两种不同的行程和
at two different price points. American
两种不同的价格。 美国
through New York, Qatar through Doha.
经纽约入境，卡塔尔经多哈入境。
With both able to offer one-stop
由于两家航空公司都能提供
itineraries that don't involve the
不涉及
others flights, they don't offer junk
其他航班的一站式行程，因此它们不会
tickets on the route, [music] meaning
在该航线上提供劣质机票，这意味着
they must offer better pricing or
它们必须提供更好的价格或
product to win the customer's business.
产品才能赢得客户的青睐。
This is far from the only example of a
这远非航空公司
non-immunized partnership between
之间非豁免合作关系的唯一案例
airlines. United has a near identical
。 美联航
arrangement with Emirates. They operate
与阿联酋航空的合作协议几乎完全相同。 他们运营
a New York to Dubai flight to feed
纽约至迪拜的航班，以便乘客转机
onward connections while Emirates
前往其他地方，而阿联酋
[music] operates to most United hubs to
航空则运营飞往大多数美联航枢纽的航班，以便
facilitate travel further into the US.
乘客前往美国更远的地方。
Deltas [music] announced a similar
Deltas [音乐] 宣布
arrangement with soon to launch Riad
与即将成立的 Riad
Air. The US airline will operate flights
Air 达成类似协议。 这家美国航空公司将运营飞往
to the new airlines hub in Riad while
里亚德新航空枢纽的航班，而
Riad Air is expected to serve major
里亚德航空预计将服务于达
Delta hubs. None of these partnerships
美航空的主要枢纽。 这些合作关系均未获得
are antitrust [music]
反垄断（音乐）
immunized. All operate nearly
豁免。 它们的运作方式几乎
identically to immunized partnerships.
与免疫伙伴关系完全相同。
partnerships if antitrust immunity
如果反垄断豁免没有弊端，那么这些合作关系是否需要反垄断豁免就无关紧要了
didn't have a downside. But the downside
。 但缺点也
is not hard to find. Italy, for example,
不难发现。 例如，意大利
[music] is a massive destination for US
（音乐）是美国游客的热门旅游目的地
travelers. From New York, there are
。 从纽约出发，有
plenty of non-stops to the major markets
很多直飞
like Milan and Rome. Four genuine
米兰、罗马等主要市场的航班。 有四家真正的
competitors fight for business on these
竞争对手在这些航线上争夺生意
routes, and pricing is therefore low. An
，因此价格很低。
in the high demand month of August. Then
在需求旺盛的八月份，平均价格分别为 566 美元和 486 美元。 此外，
there are the less competitive routes to
还有通往
smaller markets like Venice, Naples,
威尼斯、那不勒斯、
Bari, and Polarmo, where two competitors
巴里和波拉莫等较小市场的竞争较小的路线，在这些路线上，两家竞争对手会展开
duke it out head-to-head. But as you'd
正面较量。 但正如你所
expect, less competition means pricing
预料的那样，竞争减少意味着
[music] power is stronger and airfares
音乐定价权更强，机票价格
are higher. $579,
更高。  579 美元、
$578, [music]
578 美元、[音乐]
$860, and $819.
860 美元和 819 美元。
Between these four, the distinction in
这四者之间的
pricing can be even further explained by
价格差异还可以用
competitive dynamics. In Venice [music]
竞争动态来进一步解释。 在威尼斯（音乐界）
and Naples, it's United versus Delta,
和那不勒斯，就像美联航和达美航空是
true direct competitors. In Bari and
真正的直接竞争对手。 在巴里和
Polarmo, it's [music] United versus
波拉莫，是联合航空对阵
Neos, a small Italian airline with just
尼奥斯航空，这是一家小型意大利航空公司，只有
six longhaul aircraft operating once or
六架远程飞机，每周运营一到
twice [music] weekly service. With a
两次航班。 由于
limited name recognition in the US, it's
在美国的知名度有限，它
hardly a strong competitor to United for
很难成为
US origin [music] traffic, potentially
美国本土音乐客运市场中美联航的强劲竞争对手，这或许可以
explaining the higher price point on
解释这些航线价格较高的原因
these routes. Rather than engaging in a
。 与其
price war with Neos, United seems to
与 Neos 展开价格战，美联航似乎更
allow them to eat just a little bit of
愿意让 Neos 抢占一点
their lunch, as Neos consistently
市场份额，因为在这些航线上，Neos 的
charges a couple hundred less than
票价总是比美联航低几百美元
United on these routes. The sole route
。 唯一一条
without head-to-head competition to
没有直接竞争的
Italy, Deltas to Katana, does buck this
意大利航线是达美航空飞往卡塔纳的航线，它略微打破了这一
trend [music] slightly since its average
趋势[音乐]，因为其平均
pricing is just $600, but this route
票价仅为 600 美元，但这条航线
does have indirect competition [music]
确实存在来自联合航空新航的间接竞争[音乐]，
from United Neos since Polarmo is also
因为波拉莫也在
in Sicily, meaning it likely pulls from
西西里岛，这意味着它可能吸引的是
a similar pool of passengers. Looking
类似的乘客群体。
further, the Spanish market demonstrates
进一步观察，西班牙市场也呈现出
a similar trend. The most competitive
类似的趋势。 竞争最激烈的旅游
destinations, Barcelona and Madrid,
目的地，如巴塞罗那和马德里，
average the lowest, while the least
平均价格最低；而竞争最不激烈的旅游目的地
competitive, like Santiago de
，如圣地亚哥-德孔
Compostella, Bilbao, Malaga, and Pom
波斯特拉、毕尔巴鄂、马拉加和波美
America, are the highest. [music] Taken
拉尼亚，平均价格最高。  [音乐] 综合来看
together, a graph of August airfares to
，从纽约飞往
every Italian and Spanish destination
意大利和西班牙所有目的地的 8 月份机票价格图表
from New York [music] demonstrates a
[音乐]显示出一个
clear trend, the exact trend economic
清晰的趋势，这正是经济
theory would predict. The more
理论所预测的趋势。
competition a route has, the lower
航线竞争越激烈，
[music] the airfares. What one could
机票价格就越低。
infer from this is that when airlines
由此可以推断，当航空公司的
have fewer competitors, they have
竞争对手较少时，它们的
stronger pricing power, meaning they
定价权就更强，这意味着它们
have greater ability to charge
更有能力向
passengers more without losing their
乘客收取更高的费用而不会失去
business. Therefore, one could infer
业务。 因此，可以推断，
that over the Atlantic, the diminishment
在大西洋彼岸，由于
of competitiveness due to antitrust
反垄断
immunity waiverss has given airlines
豁免权的豁免导致竞争力下降，航空公司获得了
more pricing power, [music] leading to
更大的定价权，[音乐] 从而导致
higher airfares overall. There's also
机票价格整体上涨。 也有一些
anecdotal evidence of this. For example,
轶事证据可以佐证这一点。 例如，
Dublin is only 400 m or 650 km further
都柏林距离波士顿只比圣地亚哥远 400 米或 650 公里
from Boston than San Diego. JetBlue
。 捷蓝航空
flies to both destinations [music] using
使用配置相似的 A321 飞机飞往这两个目的地 [音乐]
similarly configured A321 aircraft, but
，但
their pricing between the two routes is
两条航线的定价却
dramatically different. In August,
截然不同。  8 月份，
the transcontinental [music] route, but
跨大陆[音乐]路线的平均收费为 186 美元，而
for the transatlantic one, 2 and a half
跨大西洋路线的平均收费为 476 美元，是其 2.5
times more. And even then, JetBlue is
倍。 即便如此，捷蓝航空仍然是
the lowest cost operator on this route,
这条航线上成本最低的运营商，这
perhaps because it's not part of any of
或许是因为它没有参与任何
the major joint ventures. Delta is
大型合资企业。 达美航空的
charging slightly more at $485 while
票价略高，为 485 美元，而
Airingus' seats are selling for $536.
Airingus 的票价为 536 美元。
Now, admittedly, this is imperfect
当然，这并非完美的
evidence. There [music] are some
证据。 音乐跨大西洋运营还有一些
legitimate additional costs for
合理的额外成本
transatlantic operations, like ETOP
，例如 ETOP
certification, taxes, and fees. And
认证、税费和其他费用。
airlines do use different pricing
航空公司
strategies between domestic and
在国内航线和
transatlantic that inflate the cost
跨大西洋航线上采用不同的定价策略，这推高了
[music] of oneways to Europe. But
飞往欧洲的单程机票价格。 但从
marketwide, transatlantic fairs are some
市场整体来看，跨大西洋航线是世界
of the highest cost long haul routes in
上每英里成本最高的长途航线之一
the world on a per mile basis. And
。
airlines will even admit this, at least
航空公司甚至也会承认这一点，至少会
indirectly. Here's Lu Tanza in an
间接承认。 这是 Lu Tanza 在一次
investor presentation touting that
投资者推介会上吹嘘
Transatlantic is their quote core profit
Transatlantic 是他们的核心利润
pool. And here's British Airways' parent
来源。 以下是英国航空公司母公司
thing in a transcript of an investor
在投资者演示稿中表达的大致相同观点
presentation. This all tracks with
。 这一切都与
economic theory. When there's lower
经济理论相符。 当
competition, firms have stronger pricing
竞争较小时，企业拥有更强的
power, [music] enabling them to command
定价权，[音乐]使它们能够获得
higher profits. And the problem goes
更高的利润。 而且，问题
beyond the consolidation of these
不仅仅在于这些
airlines into larger singular entities
航空公司合并成更大的单一实体，
because these larger singular entities
因为这些更大的单一实体
have been able to leverage their
已经能够利用其
dominant market positions to drive
市场支配地位，将
genuine competition out of business.
真正的竞争对手挤出市场。
Back in the late 2010s, Norwegian
2010 年代后期，挪威
Airlines made a play at long haul and
航空进军长途航线，
grew into the largest foreign carrier
发展成为服务于纽约市场的最大外国航空公司，并成为
outright behind [music] United, Delta,
仅次于联合航空、达美航空、
American BA. They were operating a
美国航空和英国航空的第五大跨大西洋航空公司。 他们采用
lowcost model, severely undercutting
低成本模式，大幅降低
their competitors' prices [music] and
竞争对手（音乐）的价格，
therefore severely threatening their
因此严重威胁到他们的市场
supremacy. In particular, it was most
主导地位。 尤其
threatening to British Airways since
对英国航空公司而言，威胁最大，因为
their main base was at London's [music]
他们的主要基地位于伦敦盖特威克
Gatwick Airport. And so BA's parent
机场。 因此，英国航空的
company, I AG did anything they could to
母公司 I AG 竭尽所能，将这家
drive the upstart carrier out of
新兴航空公司挤出
business. When Norwegian started Gatwick
市场。 当挪威航空开通盖特威克机场
to New York flights, British Airways
至纽约的航班时，英国航空也
launched Gatwick to [music] New York
开通了盖特威克机场至纽约的
flights, even though the only other long
航班，尽管
haul flights they operated from the
他们从该机场运营的其他长途航班
airport were to warm weather leisure
都是飞往温暖气候的休闲
destinations. When Norwegian started
目的地。 当挪威航空开通
Gatwick to Oakland, California flights,
盖特威克机场至加利福尼亚州奥克兰的航线时，
British Airways started Oakland flights,
英国航空也开通了奥克兰的航线，
even though they already operated
尽管他们当时已经运营着
flights to San Francisco airport a
飞往
[music] mere 10 m or 16 km away. When
仅10米（16公里）外的旧金山机场的航线。
Norwegian started Gatwick to Fort
挪威航空开通盖特威克机场至劳德
Lauderdale flights, British Airways
代尔堡的航班后，英国航空也
started Fort Lauderdale flights, even
开通了劳德代尔堡的航班，
though they already operated to Miami 20
尽管他们当时已经运营飞往 20
m or 32 km away. When Norwegian started
英里（32 公里）外的迈阿密的航班。 当挪威航空开通
Barcelona to Oakland and LA flights,
巴塞罗那至奥克兰和洛杉矶的航线时，
British Airways' parent company IIG
英国航空的母公司 IIG 也
started a [music] brand new lowcost
创办了一家名为
airline called Level and also launched
Level 的全新低成本航空公司，并开通了
Barcelona to Oakland and LA flights. The
巴塞罗那至奥克兰和洛杉矶的航线。
tactic here was obvious. I was [music]
这里的策略很明显。 我当时（在音乐方面）
trying to bleed Norwegian dry. They'd
试图榨干挪威语的精髓。 他们会与
match Norwegian's route launches,
挪威航空同步推出新航线，
saturate the market, price tickets
饱和市场，以极低的价格出售机票
aggressively low, take passengers away
，抢走
from Norwegian, and ultimately the
挪威航空的乘客，最终这一
tactic worked. Norwegian's longhaul
策略奏效了。 挪威航空的长途航线
operations started to falter in 2019.
运营在 2019 年开始出现问题。
[music] They reshuffled their network to
[音乐] 他们重新调整了航线网络，以
find routes that could work. But then
寻找可行的航线。 但由于
after a full shutdown due to CO, the
一氧化碳疫情导致全面停飞，
Norwegian never flew a longhaul flight
挪威航空的787飞机再也没有重新投入使用，挪威航空也再没有执飞过长途航班
again. Unsurprisingly, with the
。 不出所料，
exception of Barcelona to Los Angeles,
除了巴塞罗那到洛杉矶的航线外，
none of the routes [music] IG launched
IG 为与
to match Norwegian service still operate
挪威航空的服务竞争而推出的所有航线如今都已不再运营
today, further demonstrating their
，这进一步证明了他们的
[music] true intent. Given their scale,
真实意图。 考虑到它们的规模，
launch and lose money on these routes if
如果 IEG 开通这些航线并赔钱，
it prevented Norwegian from getting a
阻止挪威航空
foothold in their key markets. While
在其主要市场站稳脚跟，那么 IEG 就完全有理由这样做。 虽然
it's far from a given that Norwegian
挪威
Longhaul would have survived even
长途运输公司即使
without this anti-competitive behavior,
没有这种反竞争行为也未必能够生存下来，但
IG's actions demonstrated that they were
IG的行动表明他们
genuinely threatened and they did not
确实受到了威胁，他们并不
consider it a given that Norwegian
认为挪威
Longhaul would die out on its own. It's
长途运输公司会自行消亡。
really hard to understand American and
很难理解美国和
European regulators' logic behind
欧洲监管机构在
antitrust immunity over the Atlantic.
大西洋彼岸给予反垄断豁免的逻辑。
The public-f facing logic is clearly
面向公众的逻辑显然存在
faulty. But even if one attempts to read
缺陷。 但即使试图揣摩
between the lines, there's little logic
言外之意，也找不到什么逻辑可言
there either. It's possible that it was
。 有可能这
just a genuine mistake. That initial
只是个无心之失。
approvals in the '90s happened in the
90 年代的最初批准是在
tumultuous time following deregulation
放松管制后的动荡时期进行的，
when consequences were less understood
当时人们对后果了解甚少，
and stability and air service was a
稳定性和航空服务是
higher priority. But that mistake has
更高的优先事项。 但这个错误却像
snowballed. In recent years, the
滚雪球一样越滚越大。 近年来，
dominant [music] logic behind approvals
音乐界审批背后的主流逻辑
is that that's the way it's always been
是：一直以来都是这么做的
done. Regulators appear to be blindly
。 只要串谋行为的结构与现有串谋行为的结构相似，监管机构似乎就会盲目地
approving more and more antitrust
批准越来越多的反
immunity waiverss so long as collusion
垄断豁免
collusion. They don't want to rock the
。 他们不想
boat, but by avoiding so, they're
惹麻烦，但通过避免这样做，他们反而
helping the [music] consumers lose out,
让音乐消费者蒙受损失，而
the very people they're there to serve.
他们恰恰是要服务于这些消费者。
They're helping airlines charge more,
他们帮助航空公司提高票价，
making it slightly less accessible for
使得
everyone to hop across the pond.
跨越大西洋旅行变得更加困难。
Okay, so now I have a very real,
好的，现在我要讲一个非常真实、
slightly embarrassing story to tell as
有点尴尬的故事，作为
part of this ad re. [music] Basically,
这则广告的一部分。  [音乐]
the sponsor for this video is Rocket
这段视频的赞助商是 Rocket
Money, which I'd never actually used,
Money，我之前从未用过，
but to try them out and figure out
但为了试用一下，看看
whether I should endorse them, I
是否应该代言，我
downloaded the app and linked my bank
下载了他们的应用程序，并关联了我的银行
and credit card accounts. Admittedly,
和信用卡账户。 说实话，
I'm not always very on top of my
我有时对自己的财务状况掌控得并不好
finances. I'm fortunate enough to have
。 我很幸运，有
enough savings that I don't need to keep
足够的积蓄，所以不需要
track of every expense, but I'd also
记录每一笔开支，但我
sort of noticed recently that my account
最近也注意到我的账户
balance was getting lower than usual. I
余额比平时要低一些。 我
didn't think I was spending more or
并不觉得我的支出比平时多，
making less than normal, so I was a bit
收入比平时少，所以我有点
confused, but hadn't really looked into
困惑，但也没有真正去仔细研究过
it. But when trying out Rocket Money, I
。 但在试用 Rocket Money 时，我四处查看，
poked around and went to their recurring
然后去了他们的定期
payments tab, where they show you all
付款选项卡，在那里他们会显示你
the recurring payments you make. And
进行的所有定期付款。 就在
that's where I noticed something weird.
那里，我注意到了一些奇怪的事情。
Basically, my two biggest recurring
基本上，我每月最大的两笔固定
payments each month were to the account
支出都是支付给
of the bank that I have my mortgage
我房贷银行的账户
with. I only use that account for the
。 我只用那个账户来支付
mortgage, so I only send enough to make
房贷，所以我每个月只往里面转够
the mortgage payment [music] each month.
支付房贷的钱。
But I only pay my mortgage once a month,
但我每月只还一次房贷，
and this auto transfer was happening
而这种自动转账却
twice a month. Basically, it turns out
每月发生两次。 事情是这样的，
that about 6 months ago, I somehow
大约 6 个月前，我不
accidentally duplicated the auto
小心重复设置了自动
transfer and extra money had been
转账，导致
accumulating in this other bank account.
另一个银行账户里积累了额外的钱。
Ultimately, this worked out pretty well
最终，这笔钱花得还不错，
since I was sending the extra money to
因为我把额外的钱都给了
myself, but there were also plenty of
自己，但
other smaller subscriptions in there
里面还有很多其他的小额订阅，
that I didn't realize it was still
我没有意识到它还在
paying. So, I was able to cut back on
收费。 因此，我每月可以节省
about $100 of spending a month. As you'd
大约 100 美元的开支。 正如你所
imagine, since Rocket Money immediately
料，由于 Rocket Money 立即
proved itself, I'm now a legitimate
证明了自己的价值，我现在是一名正式
user. And there's more than just the
用户。 除了
recurring payments feature that I find
定期付款功能之外，还有更多我觉得
worthwhile. I love their automated
有价值的地方。 我非常喜欢他们的自动
spending reports as it makes it super
消费报告，因为它让
simple for me to see where I'm spending
我很容易就能看出我在哪里花了
too much money. Unsurprisingly, it's on
太多钱。 不出所料，是关于
travel. They also help you reach your
旅行的。 它们还能帮助你实现
goals as you can set a budget, then use
目标，因为你可以设定预算，然后使用
the app to track your progress sticking
该应用程序跟踪你的进度，并
to it through time. There are so many
随着时间的推移坚持下去。 除此之外还有很多
more features beyond that, but all in
其他功能，但
all, I've already found Rocket Money to
总的来说，我已经发现 Rocket Money 是
be a really useful, really simple way to
一个非常实用、非常简单的工具，可以让我
stay more on top of my finances with
更好地掌控自己的财务状况，而且
basically no work at all. So, take
基本上不需要任何操作。 所以，从
control of your finances today. Click
今天开始掌控你的财务状况吧。 点击
the link in the description or scan the
说明中的链接或扫描
QR code on screen to get started for
屏幕上的二维码即可免费开始使用
free.
。